const question = document.getElementById('question');
const choices = Array.from(document.getElementsByClassName('choice-text'));
const progressText = document.getElementById('progressText');
const scoreText = document.getElementById('score');
const progressBarFull =document.getElementById("progressBarFull");
const loader = document.getElementById("loader");
const game = document.getElementById("game");


let currentQuestion = {};
let acceptingAnswers = false;
let score = 0;
let questionCounter = 0;
let availableQuestions = [];

let questions = [
    {
        question: "Identify the first evolution of Information Age", 
        choice1: "Stone Age ",
        choice2: "Blade Tools",
        choice3: "Flake tools",
        choice4: "Bifacial ",
        answer: 1
    }, 

{
        question: "A hoe and a cutlass are examples of which age?", 
        choice1: "Middle Age",
        choice2: "Iron Age ",
        choice3: "Industrial Stage",
        choice4: "Stone Age ",
        answer: 2
    }, 
{
        question: "Electronic started with invention of _____ ", 
        choice1: "Pocket calculator",
        choice2: "Industrial Age",
        choice3: "Early stage",
        choice4: "Second Stage",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "Computer is an _______device that accept data", 
        choice1: "an Electronic Device",
        choice2: "Machine",
        choice3: "inventer",
        choice4: "Innovation",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "One of the following is the feature of a computer ", 
        choice1: "Accuracy",
        choice2: "Slows down",
        choice3: "Curb damages",
        choice4: "Discards information",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "Data is derived from latin word called _____?", 
        choice1: "an Electronic Device",
        choice2: "Data",
        choice3: "Dutum",
        choice4: "Date",
        answer: 2
 }, 
{
        question: "Processing of data is the conversion of data into a _______and _______", 
        choice1: "Meaningful and useful form",
        choice2: "Meaningless and useful form ",
        choice3: "Amazing form and super form",
        choice4: "Jainter and Wonderful",
        answer: 1
 }, 

{
        question: "The following is the key characteristics of good information", 
        choice1: "Reliability",
        choice2: "Fake information",
        choice3: "Acute",
        choice4: "Innovation",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "ICT stands for ______", 
        choice1: "Information and Communication Technology",
        choice2: "Communication Technology and Information",
        choice3: "Technology Communication and Information",
        choice4: "Information Technology and Communication",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "Computer accept data inform _____", 
        choice1: "inputs",
        choice2: "Output",
        choice3: "Results",
        choice4: "Information",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "IPO stands for ______", 
        choice1: "Input Process Output",
        choice2: "Integrated Process Output",
        choice3: "Out put Input",
        choice4: "Information Process and Out part",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "Which one of the following is the most important hardware component", 
        choice1: "System Unit",
        choice2: "System Application",
        choice3: "Printing Machine",
        choice4: "Joystick",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "A monitor is a device that display _____ and _____ generated by the computer", 
        choice1: "Images and Zoom",
        choice2: "Volumn and Contracts color",
        choice3: "Text and Images",
        choice4: "Colors and volumn",
        answer: 3
 }, 
{
        question: "A monitor is popularly known as the _______", 
        choice1: "Display Unit",
        choice2: "Color Screen",
        choice3: "Visual Diplay Unit",
        choice4: "VDU",
        answer: 3
 }, 
{
        question: "Which part of the computer provides the soft copy of results?", 
        choice1: "CPU",
        choice2: "VSD",
        choice3: "DOS",
        choice4: "Monitor",
        answer: 4
 }, 

{
        question: "______is an input device that looks like typewriter", 
        choice1: "Panio",
        choice2: "CPU",
        choice3: "Keyboard",
        choice4: "System Unit",
        answer: 3
 }, 

{
        question: "Keyboards usually have between _____to _____keys", 
        choice1: "1005 to 1139",
        choice2: "1070 to 1900",
        choice3: "1034 to 1070",
        choice4: "101 to 105",
        answer: 4
 }, 

{
        question: "A pointing device that controls the movement of the cursor is called ______", 
        choice1: "Mouse",
        choice2: "Joystick",
        choice3: "Printer",
        choice4: "Scanner",
        answer: 1
 }, 
{
        question: "Printer is an output device that produces _____and ______ on a physical medium", 
        choice1: "Angles and Triangle shapes",
        choice2: "Volumn and Contracts color",
        choice3: "Text and Graphics",
        choice4: "Colors and shapes",
        answer: 3
 }, 

{
        question: "Speakers allows you to hear the sound generated by a ________", 
        choice1: "Home theater",
        choice2: "Amplifier",
        choice3: "Speaker",
        choice4: "Sound card",
        answer: 4
 }, 

];

//CONSTANTS
const CORRECT_BONUS = 3;
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 20;

startGame = () => {
    questionCounter = 0;
    score = 0;
    availableQuestions = [...questions];
    getNewQuestion();
    game.classList.remove("hidden");
    loader.classList.add("hidden");
};

getNewQuestion = () => {

    if(availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter >=MAX_QUESTIONS){
        localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score);
        //go to the end page 
        return window.location.assign("end.html");
    }
    questionCounter++;
    progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter}/${MAX_QUESTIONS}`;
    //Update the progress bar
    progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter / MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}%`;

    const questionIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * availableQuestions.length);
    currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionIndex];
    question.innerText = currentQuestion.question;

    choices.forEach(choice => {
        const number = choice.dataset["number"];
        choice.innerText = currentQuestion["choice" + number];
    });

    availableQuestions.splice(questionIndex, 1);
    acceptingAnswers = true;
};

choices.forEach(choice => {
    choice.addEventListener("click", e => {
        if (!acceptingAnswers) return;

        acceptingAnswers = false;
        const selectedChoice = e.target;
        const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset["number"];

        //const classToApply = 'incorrect';
        //if (selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer) {
           // classToApply = 'correct';
        //}

        const classToApply = selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer ? 'correct' : 'incorrect'; 

        if (classToApply === "correct") {
            incrementScore(CORRECT_BONUS);
        }
        
        selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(classToApply);

        setTimeout( () => {
            selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(classToApply);
            getNewQuestion();

        }, 1000);
    });
});

incrementScore = num => {
    score += num;
    scoreText.innerText = score;
};

startGame();

